And as you do so, I wish to encourage
the church to keep on praying for this
nation
and more specifically pray for the
families that were affected by the fire
at Utumishi Academy.
I don't want to imagine what those
parents and families are going through
this morning. So we pray that uh those
fires have come to an end in Jesus name.
Ezra chapter number 7 I read it's a
lengthy reading so I'll read it quickly
then we get straight to hearing God's
word
the Bible says this Ezra came up from
Babylon and he was a skilled scribe in
the law of Moses which the Lord God of
Israel had given the king granted him
all his requests according to the hand
of the Lord his God upon him. Some of
the children of Israel, the priests, the
Levites, the singers, the gatekeepers,
and the Nethanim came up to Jerusalem in
the seventh year of King Aaxis.
And Ezra came to Jerusalem in the fifth
month, which was in the seventh year of
the king.
On the first day of the first month, he
began his journey from Babylon. And on
the first day of the fifth month, he
came to Jerusalem according to the good
hand of God of his God upon him.
For Ezra had prepared his heart to seek
the law of the Lord and to do it and to
teach statutes and ordinances in Israel.
This is a copy of the letter that King
Ataxis gave Ezra the priest, the scribe,
expert in the words of the commandments
of the Lord and of his statutes to
Israel.
At taxes, king of kings, to Ezra the
priest, ascribe of the law of God of
heaven, perfect peace and so forth.
I issue a decree that all those of the
people of Israel and the priests and the
levitates in my realm who volunteer to
go up to Jerusalem may go with you.
And whereas you are being sent by the
king and his seven counselors to inquire
concerning Judah and Jerusalem with
regard to the law of your God which is
in your hand.
And whereas you are to carry the silver
and gold which the king and his
counselors have freely offered to the
God of Israel whose dwelling is in
Jerusalem.
And whereas all the silver and gold that
you may find in all the province of
Babylon along with the free will
offering of the people and the priests
and to be freely offered to the for the
house of their God in Jerusalem.
Now therefore be careful to buy with
this money bulls, rams, and lamps with
their grain offerings and their drink
offerings, and offer them on the altar
of the house of God of your God in
Jerusalem.
And whatever seems good to you and your
brethren, do to do with the rest of the
silver and the gold, do it according to
the will of your God. also the articles
that are given to you for the service of
the house of your God, deliver in full
before the God of Jerusalem.
And whatever more may be needed for the
house of your God which you may have
occasion to provide, pay for it from the
king's
treasury.
And I, even I, taxes the king, issue a
decree to all the treasurers who are in
the region beyond the river, that
whatever Ezra the priest, the scribe of
the law of God of heaven, may require of
you, let it be done diligently,
up to 100 talents of silver, 100 calls
of wheat, 100 bags of wine, 100 bags of
oil, and salt without prescription. ride
limits.
Whatever is commanded by the God of
heaven, let it diligently be done for
the house of the God OF HEAVEN. FOR WHY
SHOULD THERE be wrath against the realm
of the king and his sons?
Also we inform you that it shall not be
lawful to impose tax, tribute or custom
on any of the priests, levers, singers,
gatekeepers, neim or servants of this
house of God.
And you, Ezra, according to your
God-given wisdom,
set magistrates and judges, who may
judge all the people who are in the
region beyond the river, all such as
know the laws of your God, and teach
those who do not know them.
Whoever will not observe the law of your
God or the law of the king, let judgment
be executed speedily on him, whether it
be death or banishment or confification
or goods of goods or imprisonment.
Blessed be the Lord God of our fathers,
who has put such a thing as this in the
king's heart,
to beautify the house of the Lord, which
is in Jerusalem,
and has extended mercy to me before the
king and his counselors, and before all
the king's mighty priestesses,
So I was encouraged as the hand of the
Lord my God was upon me and I gathered
leading men of Israel to go up with me.
Look at your neighbor, tell your
neighbor the good hand of the Lord.
Look at somebody else and tell them the
good hand of the Lord.
Let us pray.
Heavenly Father, in the name of Jesus,
we thank you this morning.
Such a great delight to gather to hear
your word.
Your word is forever anointed.
But I beseech you this morning that you
would anoint every faculty of my being
that I may declare your oracles with
clarity and with power. Holy Spirit of
the living God, may you take over.
Address every need in this house this
morning. Challenge our minds and our
hearts to move to where we are supposed
to be. May you be glorified at the end
of the day in Jesus name we pray. Can
somebody say a big amen?
>> You may have your seats in God's
presence.
the good
hand
of the Lord.
One of the most laborious and demanding
tasks
is to rebuild
or reconstruct
a building that has been damaged
and is in ruins.
It is even more a doubting task
especially if you want to make it LOOK
FAR MUCH better
than in it from its former state.
It is important to note
that in life
you will be confronted by the reality
and the need to repair
to rebuild
or even reconstruct
something
in your life.
Any qualified
builder
must equally
become
excellent in repair,
restoration,
and reconstruction.
IT GETS MORE complex
if you have to restore,
rebuild,
AND RECONSTRUCT A life that the enemy
almost
destroyed.
The scriptures before us this morning,
they are against a backdrop of intense
repair
and rebuilding of the walls in Jerusalem
coupled with the building of God's
house.
Ezra,
a contemporary of Nehemiah,
both of which give a detailed account
of their exit from Babylon
where they had been held captive for
over 70 years as captured by prophet
Jeremiah who prophesied that they would
get out of Babylon after 70 years AND OF
WHICH DANIEL WAS ABLE to observe by the
books.
SO THIS ACTUALLY HAPPENS TO BE SOME SORT
of their secondled exodus.
The first exodors, the children of
Israel are coming out of Egypt and from
the hand of their oppressors,
the Egyptians.
Now they are coming out of Babylon where
they had been held captive by King
Nebuchadnezzar.
BUT IT IS IMPORTANT TO NOTE
that the children of Israel have been
going through a vicious cycle
that the Lord delivers them.
Then they get into a season of comfort
and familiarity.
Then sin
creeps in.
Then God allows oppressors to come upon
them. They cry to God and God delivers
them. It happens again and again that
God delivers them. They get comfortable
and familiar.
Sin creeps in. The oppressors come upon
them. THEY CRY TO GOD and God
delivers them.
IT IS A VICIOUS CYCLE
THAT I BELIEVE THAT CHRIST JESUS came to
break
because it IS A CYCLE OF MOST people
that you go through deliverance.
You get comfortable and familiar.
Sin creeps in. THE OPPRESSOR COMES UPON
YOU. YOU CRY TO GOD AND GOD delivers
you.
But it's my prayer that this MORNING WE
WILL APPRECIATE THE WORK ACCOMPLISHED BY
Jesus on that cross according to Romans
chapter 6 and verse number 10. And this
is what the Bible says.
FOR THE DEATH THAT HE DIED, HE DIED TO
sin
once
for all. But the life that he lives, he
lives to God. I want you to look at your
neighbor for me and tell your neighbor
the cycle has been broken.
SO THE CHILDREN OF ISRAEL,
THEY are literally in another cycle
THAT GOD HAS DECIDED TO BRING THEM OUT
OF Babylon and take them back to
Jerusalem.
THE REBUILDING OF THE WALLS OF Jerusalem
and of GOD'S HOUSE
HAPPENS in the midst of immense
opposition
and resistance to the extent THAT AT
SOME POINT THE work had stalled.
Ezra 4 and verse number 24, the Bible
speaks of how thus the work of the house
of God which is at Jerusalem ceased and
it was discontinued
until the second year of the REIGN OF
DARIAT, KING OF PIA. The resistance,
the opposition
had actually made the work of
rebuilding,
RECONSTRUCTING,
restoration
to be stopped. IT IS IMPORTANT TO NOTE
THAT THE ENEMY DOESN'T WANT YOU TO
rebuild your life. He wishes to resist
you. He wishes to oppose you. AND YOU
MUST BE SPIRITUALLY AWARE THAT AS YOU
TRY TO REBUILD, RECONSTRUCT YOUR LIFE,
THERE WILL BE RESISTANCE.
Nehemiah 4 and verse number one speaks
of the same thing. BUT IT SO HAPPENED
WHEN S. BALLOT HEARD THAT WE were
rebuilding the wall that he was furious
and very indignant and mocked the Jews.
THERE ARE MANY BALLOTS AND TOBIAS OF OUR
DAY WHO WILL NOT WANT TO SEE YOU COME UP
AGAIN. FOR IN EVERY SETBACK THERE SHOULD
ALWAYS BE A COMEBACK.
OH, CAN I TALK TO SOMEBODY this morning?
I declare this morning, you need to
understand it doesn't matter the setback
you have suffered OVER THE YEARS. IN
EVERY SETBACK
WITH GOD, THERE MUST BE A COMEBACK.
So in the midst of great and intense
opposition
and resistance,
YOU CANNOT AVOID TO NOTICE
THAT GOD'S HAND,
GOD'S DIVINE FAVOR,
GOD'S RESCUE, GOD'S SUPERNATURAL
PROVISION was also evident
THAT IN THE MIDST OF CHAOS,
AND IN THE MIDST OF LACK AND IN THE
MIDST OF WAR AND RESISTANCE,
GOD WILL ALWAYS FIND A WAY TO RESCUE HIS
PEOPLE, DELIVER THEM, AND PROVIDE FOR
THEM.
IT IS IN THE NATURE OF GOD THAT HE WILL
NOT ALLOW YOU TO BE DESTROYED.
YOU COULD BE CHALLENGED, BUT HE WILL NOT
PERMIT THE ENEMY TO UTTERLY DESTROY YOU.
YOU WILL BE TEMPTED, BUT YOU PROVIDE A
WAY OF ESCAPE. THAT IN THE MIDST OF
RESISTANCE, OPPOSITION, GOD WILL ALWAYS
PROVIDE A WAY OF ESCAPE.
So Ezra,
the Bible says he was a priest
and a very skilled scribe
known for leading a group of Jewish
exile back to Jerusalem from Babylon.
Ezra spearheaded major spiritual revival
CENTERED ON THE STUDY AND OBSERVANCE OF
the law of God or the Torah.
EZRA DEDICATED HIS LIFE TO STUDYING,
PRACTICING, TEACHING, and modeling the
law of God to THE CHILDREN OF ISRAEL.
ENSURING THAT THE COMMUNITY FOLLOWED THE
TORAH. THE MAN WAS COMMITTED TO
STUDYING, to practicing, to teaching,
AND TO MODELING. MAY WE DESIRE THIS
DIMENSION OF SPIRITUALITY. OH, look at
your neighbor, tell your neighbor,
neighbor, neighbor, neighbor.
There is a place to ascend to.
Oh, in our walk with God
WHERE WE DESIRE
THAT WE STUDY, WE PRACTICE, we teach,
AND WE MODEL THE WORD OF GOD. I PRAY FOR
YOU THIS MORNING THAT YOU WILL ASCEND TO
THIS LEVEL WHERE YOU DESIRE TO STUDY,
YOU DESIRE TO PRACTICE, YOU DESIRE TO TO
MODEL, AND YOU DESIRE TO TEACH the law
of God. Hallelujah somebody.
So the Bible is very clear. He read the
law aloud to the people of Jerusalem in
public assembly.
IT SPARK WIDESPREAD revival
through weeping repentance and a renewal
of their covenant with God.
IT WAS SO INTENSE THIS REVIVAL. EZRA WAS
SO INTENSE in his understanding
THAT HE EVEN ENCOURAGED A MOVEMENT WHERE
ISRAELITES WERE TO SEPARATE themselves
from bargain influences.
And it included CONTROVERSIAL MANDATE to
divorce and send away their foreign
wives to maintain RELIGIOUS PURITY.
IMAGINE
HE WAS SO COMMITTED THAT he even advised
he even said that IF YOU HAVE MARRIED
PAGANS YOU HAVE TO DIVORCE and release
them.
So Ezra
is at the center of rebuilding,
reconstructing,
restoration,
AND MOST IMPORTANTLY, REVIVAL
IN ISRAEL. WHAT A POWERFUL MANDATE
bestowed upon A MAN.
I PRAY FOR YOU THIS MORNING THAT YOU
WILL RECEIVE A DIVINE ASSIGNMENT AND A
MANDATE THAT will change lives.
Oh, that's a weak amen. Look at your
neighbor. Tell your neighbor, neighbor,
neighbor, neighbor.
You can say a better amen.
Tell your neighbor, neighbor, receive
the mandate
for a great assignment
here on earth.
But most people have no idea
what it takes
to mobilize
to mobilize a people, ORGANIZE THEM,
INFLUENCE THEM, REDIRECT their focus
back unto God and cause revival.
IT'S HARD WORK.
IT'S REAL HARD WORK THAT EZRA BY THE
GRACE OF GOD WAS ABLE TO MOBILIZE THEM,
organize them, challenge them AND
REDIRECT THEIR FOCUS BACK UNTO GOD. THAT
IS NOT POSSIBLE.
NOT UNLESS SOMETHING is upon you. It's
not possible
at this time. Ezra. Bible scholars
believe that he was in his 30s
when he was leading this mighty revival.
It is important to note
that for every young person, do I have
some young people in the house?
Uh look at your neighbor telling your
neighbor neighbor. It's either you are
young in age or you are young at heart.
Ask them, "What are you?"
Are they saying both?
Ezra
was a young man. Bible scholars, they
believe he was in his status. AND I WANT
TO ENCOURAGE EVERY YOUNG PERSON HERE,
give God the best of your ears and not
the last of your ears.
Are you LISTENING TO ME? SERVE THE LORD
WHILE YOU STILL have the energy.
Huh? Serve the Lord while you still have
the time. If you're IF YOU'RE SINGLE, DO
IT NOW.
A time is coming when you be married.
And before you step out of that door,
you'll have to explain where, with, who,
when are you coming back.
EH, SO DO IT NOW.
DO IT NOW. EZRA WAS A YOUNG MAN WHEN HE
WAS DOING IT. YOU CAN DO IT NOW.
Somebody say amen.
>> How did he manage
TO IGNITE SUCH GREAT REVIVAL?
HOW DID HE MANAGE TO REVOLUTIONIZE
AND SET STANDARDS OF WORSHIP AND
SERVICE?
HOW DID HE MANAGE?
YOU SEE, IN OUR DAY, WE NEED TO RETHINK
WHAT IS SERVICE TO GOD. HEY, can I talk
to you? WE NEED TO RETHINK WHAT IS
SERVICE TO GOD.
MOST OF THE THINGS WE CALL SERVICE TO
GOD, YOU CAN ACTUALLY DO IT WITHOUT THE
WHOLE HELP OF THE Holy Spirit.
Nonbelievers can play keyboard
yeah.
Yeah.
BUT NON-BELIEVERS CANNOT HEAL WHILE
playing the keyboard.
Non-believers can stand AT THE DOOR AND
GREET PEOPLE. into a sanctuary.
BUT NON-BELIEVERS CANNOT GREET PEOPLE
COMING INTO CHURCH AND THEY ARE HEALED
RIGHT AT THE DOOR.
SO ANYTHING YOU DO AND YOU'RE SAYING
YOU'RE DOING FOR GOD AND IT'S NOT
DEPENDENT AND RELYING ON THE POWER OF
THE HOLY GHOST, you need to rethink it.
NONBELIEVERS CAN SING.
OH, those vocals,
THEY CAN SING. BUT NONBELIEVERS CANNOT
SING AND A walks.
ANYTHING YOU DO IN CHURCH WITHOUT
DEPENDING AND RELYING ON THE HOLY
SPIRIT, YOU NEED TO DISCLO cancel that.
That's not service.
SERVICE TO GOD MUST BE RELYING ON THE
POWER OF GOD. WE are about to look at
that.
SO WHAT WAS THE SECRET TO SUCH GREAT
ACHIEVEMENT?
The secret is in verse 6, verse 9 and
verse 28. What does it say?
What was the secret?
THE BIBLE SAYS THIS EZRA CAME UP from
Babylon and he was a skilled scribe in
the law of Moses which the Lord God of
Israel had given him. I want us to read
this other part.
The king did what?
Uh-huh.
Uh-huh. According to what?
According to what?
Go to verse number nine.
On the first day of the first MONTH, HE
BEGAN HIS JOURNEY from Babylon. AND ON
THE FIRST DAY OF THE FIRST FIFTH MONTH,
he came TO JERUSALEM ACCORDING LET'S
READ. According to the
Oh, WAIT A MINUTE. ACCORDING TO THE good
hand of his God upon him. VERSE 28. SAME
CHAPTER.
Verse 28. What does he say? And has
extended mercy to me before the king and
his counselors and before the king's
mighty. So listen, let's read that
together. So
uh-huh.
AS THE HAND OF THE LORD MY God was aon
me. Uh-huh.
Look at your neighbor. Tell your
neighbor, neighbor, neighbor, neighbor.
There is something called the hand of
the Lord.
I look at them and tell them it's a GOOD
HAND.
THERE IS ABSOLUTELY NO WAY EZRA WOULD
HAVE MANAGED TO DO ALL that he did. THE
SECRET IS THE GOOD HAND OF THE LORD WAS
UPON HIM.
This service is for A PEOPLE WHO DESIRE
THAT THIS GOOD HAND OF the Lord will be
upon them.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. YEAH. I SAY THIS
SERVICE IS FOR A PEOPLE WHO DESIRE THAT
THE GOOD HAND OF THE LORD will be upon
them. Shout a big amen. SAY WITH ME, I
DESIRE THAT THE GOOD HAND of the Lord
will be UPON ME.
IF THE GOOD HAND of the Lord
is good, IT MEANS GOD is good.
Yeah. Yeah. Let me give you scriptures.
Genesis 1 and verse 31. Psalm 3 and
verse 2 quickly LET'S GO THERE. YOU
CANNOT GIVE WHAT YOU ARE NOT.
GOD IS GOOD AND NO WONDER his hand is
good.
God is good and no wonder his hand is
good. Then God saw everything that he
had made and indeed it was
I CAN'T HEAR. IT WAS VERY GOOD. SO
WHATEVER HE DOES, HE DOES IT. HE DOES IT
IN A GOOD WAY. HEY, LOOK AT YOUR
NEIGHBOR. TELL YOUR NEIGHBOR, "IN A good
way."
>> Are you ready for me this morning?
>> Psalm 103 and verse number two. THE
BIBLE SAYS, "BLESS THE LORD, OH MY SOUL,
AND FORGET NOT ALL HIS BENEFITS."
BENEFITS, GOODNESS. PSALM 145 AND VERSE
number nine.
Let's read THAT ALL TOGETHER. THE LORD
IS GOOD TO ALL AND HIS TENDER MERCIES
ARE ALL OVER HIS WORKS. THE LORD IS GOOD
TO ALL. GOD IS A GOOD GOD. Look at your
neighbor for me. TELL GOD IS A GOOD GOD.
Tell your neighbor what is coming your
way is going to be good. It's going to
be good. It's going to be good. It's
going to be good. Psalm 34 and verse
number eight. Some of that. Oh. Oh my
god. Let's read.
Oh, taste and uhhuh
that the Lord IS
BLESSED IS A MAN WHO TRUSTS IN HIM. OH,
TASTE AND SEE THAT THE LORD IS GOD IS A
GOOD GOD. WE NEED TO COME TO A PLACE
WHERE WE START BELIEVING HIM FOR GOOD
THINGS. Philippians 1 and VERSE NUMBER
SIX, GOD IS A GOOD GOD. WE NEED TO COME
TO A PLACE WHERE WE BELIEVE HIM AND
TRUST HIM FOR GOOD THINGS. TELL YOUR
NEIGHBOR, NEIGHBOR, NEIGHBOR, I
anticipate, I expect good things.
THE BIBLE SAYS, BEING CONFIDENT of this
very thing, let's read that together,
that he
who has begun, so he has begun a good
work in you will complete it until the
day of Jesus Christ. Tell your neighbor,
NEIGHBOR, NEIGHBOR, GOD IS A GOOD GOD.
OH, I refuse the lie of the devil who
WOULD CONVINCE TRY TO CONVINCE ME THAT
GOD is not good towards me. I might be
facing a challenge right now, but God
remains to be a good God. God remains to
be a loving father. He remains to be a
caring God. He remains to BE A
SUPPORTIVE GOD. IT DOESN'T MATTER THE
SEASON IN MY LIFE. GOD IS A GOOD GOD.
OH, TASTE AND SEE, for the LORD IS GOOD.
I HAVE TESTED HIM. ASK YOUR NEIGHBOR,
HAVE YOU TESTED THE LORD? HE IS A GOOD
GOD.
And the Bible says
verse 6, verse 9, and verse 28,
according to the good hand of the Lord
that was upon Ezra.
Then I began to LOOK AND STUDY
WHAT is this that this good hand of the
Lord was able to do. BUT IT IS IMPORTANT
TO NOTE THAT THE GOOD HAND OF THE Lord
translates and conotes favor.
WHEN THE HAND OF GOD IS UPON YOU, IT
conots favor. Tell your neighbor, I'm
highly favored.
You know, some of you, the enemy has
really pushed you this week, but I'm
here to hammer it in YOUR SPIRIT. YOU
ARE HIGHLY FAVORED.
>> OH, I WANT TO SHOUT TO YOUR EARS. YOU
I SAY YOU ARE HIGHLY FAVORED. I SAY YOU
ARE HIGHLY FAVORED.
The hand of God also connotes blessing.
And to be blessed IS TO BE EMPOWERED TO
DO WELL EVEN in the most unlikely
circumstances.
That whether they place you in the
desert, you still do well. WHETHER THEY
PLACE YOU AND TRANSFER YOU TO ANOTHER
DEPARTMENT, you still thrive. Actually
those departments are thriving because
you ARE THERE. WHETHER THEY SELL YOU OUT
TO EGYPT LIKE JOSEPH, YOU'LL BECOME RICH
WHERE WHERE THEY TAKING YOU.
AM I TALKING TO SOMEBODY THIS MORNING?
SAY WITH ME, I AM BLESSED.
THE HAND OF GOD CONOTES A BLESSING.
THERE'S A BLESSING OVER YOUR LIFE.
THERE'S A BLESSING OVER MY LIFE. I WILL
DO WELL WHETHER PEOPLE LIKE IT OR NOT.
WHETHER YOU TRANSFER ME OR NOT, THE
GRACE OF GOD THAT GIVES WELL IS UPON MY
LIFE. I AM BLESSED.
STAND ON YOUR FEET. AND I WANT YOU TO
SHOUT UNTIL THE WITCHES IN YOUR VILLAGE
HERE. I AM BLESSED.
YOU'VE BEEN FEARING GOING BACK TO THE
VILLAGE WITH YOUR MERCEDES AND WITH YOUR
RANGE ROVER BECAUSE YOU FEAR THEY WILL
LOOK AT YOU WITH A BAD EYE. I WANT YOU
TO SHOUT, "I AM BLESSED."
OH, LOOK AT YOUR NEIGHBOR FOR ME AND
TELL YOUR NEIGHBOR, "THE HAND OF GOD IS
UPON MY LIFE."
Sit down. Let me talk to you.
The hand of God.
Let me give you about six things, then
I'm out of your way of this good hand.
what it did to Ezra and is going to do
to you.
The hand of God
he marked him.
That simply means verse number six.
Verse number six. I want you to
understand
when God marks you, it simply means he
makes you noticeable.
It means he set you aside.
He means you are no longer obscure.
Means you're no longer hidden.
He marks you and he brings you to the
four
and he announces you to everybody.
I got a feeling somebody's just about to
be announced.
be announced. You will have to say no
word. But the Lord God will make sure
you are announced. When you when you ear
marked, you are announced. You are set
aside. You are presented.
How am I FEELING LIKE SOMEBODY'S JUST
ABOUT TO BE PRESENTED?
YEAH. It's going to happen. Somebody
say, "Amen." The Bible says in verse
number six, "And he W EZRA CAME UP FROM
Babylon
and he was a skilled scribe in the law
of Moses." I want you to know THERE WERE
OTHER SCRIBES DURING that time.
But because Ezra his the hand of God was
upon him, he was noticed.
He was pulled out. He was recognized. He
was set on stage. I what I'm saying is
what is going to HAPPEN TO YOU BECAUSE
THE HAND OF GOD IS UPON your life. I see
the LORD MOCKING YOU. I SEE HIM SETTING
YOU ASIDE. I SEE HIM PULLING YOU OUT. I
SEE HIM SETTING THE STAGE FOR YOU. I SEE
LIGHT COMING SHINING UPON YOUR LIFE. YOU
WILL NO LONGER BE HIDDEN. SOME OF YOU,
YOU'LL BE SO HIDDEN FOR SO LONG AND YOU
ARE SO GIFTED. THE DEVIL IS A LIAR. YOU
ARE COMING UP. YOU ARE COMING OUT. YOU
WILL SHINE.
The hand of God upon Ezra caused him to
be ear marked. Number two,
the hand of God was responsible for
empowering him.
The same verse number six, THE BIBLE
SAYS THIS EZRA CAME UP FROM Babylon and
he was a skilled scribe in the law of
Moses which the Lord God of Israel had
given. I want us to read the next verse.
What does it say? The next part. The
king.
The king.
Huh?
We are reading English, not Chinese. Not
the king did what? Granted him some
requests.
The king IGNORED HIM. THE BIBLE SAYS THE
king
or
according
you know how difficult it is to have
items
a series of requests
and you go to your boss or to your
senior and he grants you all of THEM
CHANCES ARE YOU EVEN GOING to him you
know some of them will be
removed
BUT FOR A KING TO GRANT SOMEONE ALL HIS
REQUESTS. It is the hand of God ready to
empower you. YOU ARE GOING TO BE SO
EMPOWERED
THAT PEOPLE WILL NOT RESIST TO GIVE YOU
WHAT you need.
I can I talk to YOU THEY YOU ARE
IRRESISTIBLE. TELL YOUR NEIGHBOR I'M
IRRESISTIBLE.
I not that I'M SO BEAUTIFUL, NOT THAT
I'M SO HANDSOME, BUT BECAUSE THE HAND OF
GOD IS UPON MY LIFE, ALL MY REQUESTS
WILL BE GRANTED. WHATEVER I PRESENT, IT
SHALL BE GRANTED. CAN YOU SHOUT A BIG
AMEN? SAY WITH ME, I BELIEVE THAT THE
HAND OF GOD THAT EMPOWERS
is upon my life.
You have suffered
a request being rejected.
Sometimes not even rejected, not even
hard. You wanted to go make a request.
You were told don't you dare come to my
office.
You were you were resisted before you
SHOWED UP. OTHER TIMES YOU MAKE A
REQUEST and the request were oh
rejected. Other times YOU MAKE A REQUEST
AND PARTIAL RESPONSE.
WHAT GRACE is coming upon us this
morning IS THE GRACE FOR 100% RESPONSE.
I SAY I IS A GRACE FOR 100% REQUEST
COMING to be responded by JEHOVAH GOD. I
PROPHESY OVER YOUR LIFE THIS WEEK.
WHATEVER YOU WILL REQUEST THIS WEEK, IT
SHALL BE GRANTED UNTO YOU 100%.
DO I HAVE SOME PEOPLE WHO HAVE FAITH? DO
I HAVE SOME PEOPLE WHO BELIEVE THERE IS
A HAND OF GOD THAT CAN CHANGE THEIR
LIFE? I DECLARE, I DECREE THAT THIS
WEEK, WHATEVER REQUESTS YOU MAKE BEFORE
GOD, THEY SHALL BE ANSWERED.
>> The king
empowered the guy.
EMPOWERED THE GUY SO MUCH WITH ALL THAT
he requested, everything he requested.
HEY, HEY, YOUR STORY IS CHANGING. I SAY
YOUR STORY IS CHANGING. I SAY YOUR STORY
IS CHANGING. SOMEBODY IN AUTHORITY IS
GOING TO GIVE directives
empowered.
Oh, I refuse to finish the here without
being empowered.
Those requests that are delayed, WE
DECLARE THIS RIGHT NOW. THOSE REQUESTS
THAT ARE DELAYED, WE SPEAK ACCELERATION.
THEY WILL BE ANSWERED. THEY WILL BE
RESPONDED TO. IF YOU BELIEVE IT, SHOUT A
BIG AMEN. HIGH FIVE YOUR NEIGHBOR AS YOU
STAND ON YOUR FEET AND TELL YOUR
NEIGHBOR, NEIGHBOR, NEIGHBOR, NEIGHBOR.
NO MORE REJECTION.
ALL YOUR REQUESTS WILL BE GRANTED. UH
YOU'RE ABOUT TO BE EMPOWERED FOR YOUR
NEXT LEVEL. YOU NEED THE HAND OF GOD
OVER YOUR LIFE FOR YOU TO MOVE TO THE
NEXT LEVEL. IF YOU BELIEVE IT, SHOUT A
BIG AMEN.
>> Sit down for a minute.
Oh, glory.
Number three, the hand of God upon him
endorsed him.
Verse number 13 and 14.
The king issues a decree.
You know when a king issues a decree,
there is no legislature
or legislative assembly that can veto
that or change that.
When a king issues a decree, it becomes
law.
So the king decides I will ENDORSE THIS
GUY with a DECREE SO THAT WHATEVER I am
doing is permanent.
Huh? Can I talk to you? So the king
decides Ezra BECAUSE OF THE ASSIGNMENT
OVER YOUR LIFE AND BECAUSE THE HAND OF
GOD WAS UPON him the king was prompted
by God to issue A DECREE SO THAT NOBODY
CAN CHANGE IT.
SO THAT IT BECOMES PERMANENT. Can I
announce to you when THE HAND OF GOD IS
upon your life, the endorsement that is
coming is going to be permanent.
WE CANCEL THIS BACK AND FORTH THAT YOU
GET something today, they demote YOU
TOMORROW. HEY, THEY GIVE YOU MONEY
TODAY, they come for it tomorrow. THEY
GIVE YOU GIFTS TODAY, BOYFRIENDS, THEN
THEY COME FOR THOSE GIFTS TOMORROW. THE
DEVIL IS A LIAR. IT'S GOING TO BE
PERMANENT.
THE ENDORSEMENT THAT IS COMING UPON YOU
IS GOING TO HAVE A SEAL THAT REALLY SAYS
IT CANNOT BE TAKEN away from them. May
the Lord seal it in heaven. May the Lord
give you SOMETHING THAT IS SEALED BY THE
HEAVENS ITSELF THAT IT CANNOT IT WILL
NOT IT SHALL NOT BE TAKEN AWAY. SAY I AM
ENDORSED BY GOD.
SO THE king endorses this guy, qualifies
him so that nobody will ever question
his qualifications.
Nobody
because the good hand of the Lord was
upon him. And then because he knew if I
allow my assistant to send him,
he may find another assistant to stop
him. So the Bible says in verse number
15, 15, look at verse 15. And whereas
you are to carry silver and gold which
the king and his counselors. Okay, let
me go back to verse 14. Look still verse
14.
Okay, the king. IT IS THE KING. AND
WHEREAS YOU ARE BEING SENT BY who was
sending him?
I can't hear you. Who was sending him?
Ask your neighbor. Neighbor. Neighbor.
Are you able TO READ? WHO WAS sending
him?
So that means if the KING SENDS YOU,
NOBODY can take you back.
Because if THE ASSISTANT OR THE GOVERNOR
WAS THE ONE sending him, any other
governor can stop him. But if IT'S THE
KING, NOBODY CAN SEND HIM BACK.
Some of us, we need such level of
ENDORSEMENT
THAT COMES WITH A DECREE THAT COMES WITH
A SENDING LETTER THAT WHERE YOU ARE
GOING, THE LETTER WILL SPEAK FOR ITSELF.
ACTUALLY,
I'm coming. We are ready to receive you.
We have seen who has signed it. Hey.
Hallelujah. May the Lord endorse you. I
said, may the Lord endorse you. Receive
an endorsement from heaven. YOU'VE BEEN
CRYING for men to endorse you, BUT MAY
THE LORD ENDORSE you this morning. CAN
YOU SHOUT A BIG AMEN?
>> Number four, because the hand of the
Lord was upon him, it made him
exceptional.
You read the scripture in verse number
six
and the Bible says there's an adjective
that describes him.
Ezra became came up from Babylon and he
was a skilled
skilled
scribe. Skilled scribe. That word you
don't don't just use it on anybody.
Even at your place of work, you don't
just say this man is skilled.
You must have experience, encountered
their expertise
and the ability to perform, execute and
give results.
SO BECAUSE THE HAND OF GOD was upon
Ezra, he was very outstanding to the
extent that the Bible describes him as
skilled.
Exceptionalism is a grace.
Exceptionalism is a grace that comes
upon a people that when you become a
musician, you become an exceptional
musician,
skilled one who amongst musicians you
stand out. That you become a manager
THAT YOU ARE SO EXCEPTIONAL THAT AMONGST
the manager the CEO can say you are
skilled, you are outstanding, you are
peculiar, you are unique.
IT SOUNDS LIKE THE GRACE THAT operates
in the sons of God. So I'm here to
announce TO YOU THAT THE HAND OF GOD
WHEN IT'S UPON YOUR LIFE, YOU WILL BE
EXCEPTIONAL. Receive the grace to be
exceptional.
>> RECEIVE. MAY YOU COME OUT OF MEDIOCRITY.
COME OUT OF THE AVERAGE. BE OUTSTANDING.
BE PECULIAR IN WHATSOEVER YOU TOUCH TO
DO. MAY IT HAVE THE MARK OF GOD. SHOUT
WITH ME, EXCEPTIONAL. SAY WITH ME, I AM
EXCEPTIONAL.
And verse number 21 and 23, the king
INSISTS THAT WHATEVER HAS to be done, it
has to be done diligently.
Diligently. Again, that word, you don't
use it uh loosely. It's a word you use
for outstanding exceptional assignments.
So I pray that YOU CAPTURE THE GRACE FOR
EXCEPTIONALISM.
THAT WHEREVER WE GO, WHATEVER WE DO,
WHATEVER ASSIGNMENT THAT IS THROWN YOUR
WAY, you're going to stand out. You'll
be exceptional. Receive the grace to be
exceptional. SHOUT A BIG AMEN.
>> AMEN.
>> Number five,
the hand of God upon Ezra made him to be
exempted from certain things.
Verse number 24, what does it say?
Look at this. He was exempted. Hey,
also we inform you that it shall not be
I want you to read. It shall not be to
do what?
Uh-huh. Uh-huh. Uh-huh. on any
Uh-huh. Levites, singers, gatekeepers,
neaning or servants of this house of so
Ezra and his team they were exempted
from paying tax.
When the hand of God is upon your life,
YOU WILL BE EXEMPTED from certain
things. Some of you, you only think that
you have to pay for everything. No. WHEN
THE HAND OF GOD IS UPON YOU, THERE IS
SOME SOMEBODY coming telling you don't
pay for that.
YEAH. ARE YOU READY FOR THIS NEW LEVEL?
>> I SAY ARE YOU READY FOR THIS NEW LEVEL?
I HAVE SAT IN PLACES WHERE I DIDN'T know
whom I was sitting with enjoyed a meal
and when I'm done I am here. It has been
paid.
It has been paid. I WAS EXEMPTED from
pain. THERE IS A GRACE THAT CAN COME
UPON YOU THAT YOU DON'T HAVE TO PAY FOR
EVERYTHING.
If you're clapping, you can clap better.
THERE IS A GRACE THAT CAN COME UPON YOUR
LIFE THAT YOU ACTUALLY DON'T HAVE TO PAY
for everything. I WANT YOU TO SHOUT BY
FAITH WITH ME AND SAY, I DON'T HAVE TO
PAY FOR EVERYTHING.
IF THE HAND OF GOD IS UPON YOUR LIFE,
YOU REALLY DON'T HAVE TO PAY FOR
EVERYTHING.
>> YOU DON'T HAVE OTHERWISE. WHAT'S THE
DIFFERENCE between us and unbelievers?
The difference between us and
unbelievers is this that we have a God
who placed his hand upon our lives and
we are exempted from certain things. We
are even exempted from processes.
God can exempt you from queuing
that you're told uh your visa you can
only come in June then they send an
email the next day exception and says
there's a slot that has come up are you
available tomorrow
exemption I SAY EXEMPTION MAY YOU
RECEIVE THE SAME GRACE WHERE YOU'LL BE
EXEMPTED FROM CERTAIN THINGS YOU ARE
MEANT TO PAY FOR YOU WILL NOT PAY FOR
BECAUSE THE HAND OF GOD IS UPON YOUR
LIFE. IF YOU BELIEVE IT, SHOUT A BIG
AMEN.
Do I have SOME BELIEVERS IN THE HOUSE
WHO BELIEVE THAT THEY CAN BE EXEMPTED? I
SPEAK OVER YOUR LIFE. UH A GRACEFUL
EXEMPTION. UH YOU DON'T HAVE TO PAY FOR
EVERYTHING. THE HAND OF GOD IS UPON YOUR
LIFE.
Oh God,
exemption.
you will be exempted.
I'm about to finish
because the hand of God was upon him. It
was responsible for his elevation.
Look at verse number 25.
Ezra
was a priest. Are we together?
But because of the hand of God upon him,
the grace of God upon his life,
Ezra, look at what it says. And you,
Ezra, according to your God-given what?
So the king actually acknowledges there
is something called God-given what? Say,
I receive it.
May people recognize you have unique
wisdom.
It is God-given wisdom.
So according to your God-given wisdom,
do what? Set magistrates and judges who
may judge all the people who are in the
region beyond THE RIVER. ALL SUCH AS
know the laws of your God and teach
those who do not know them. Look, a
priest now has gone into governance
elevation.
He came to KING ATAXIS AS A PRIEST. BY
THE TIME HE WAS LEAVING, HE HAS THE
MANDATE to do governors elevation.
WHAT IS COMING UPON YOU IS PUSHING you
to territories you never imagined.
>> Responsibilities that you never thought
would come your way. They will be PUSHED
YOUR WAY. WHY? THE HAND OF GOD IS UPON
YOUR LIFE. IT WAS SO STRONG A MANDATE.
LOOK AT THE NEXT VERSE. IT WAS SUCH A
STRONG MANDATE. THE BIBLE SAYS, "WHOEVER
WILL NOT OBSERVE THE LAW OF YOUR GOD AND
THE LAW OF THE KING, LET JUDGMENT BE
executed speedly on him."
Elevation
because what? The good hand of the Lord
was upon him. I see elevation. I see
promotion. It doesn't come from the east
or west. It comes from above. I see God
picking you up, giving you
responsibilities that you will be like,
"Oh, God, how did you even imagine I can
do this?" It is because THE HAND OF GOD
IS UPON YOUR LIFE. IF YOU BELIEVE IT,
SAY, "AMEN."
>> And lastly, the Bible says, "The hand of
God, because of the hand of the Lord,
Ezra says, I was encouraged."
number 28
he says I was encouraged
and has extended mercy on me before the
king and his customers and before the
all mighty kings mighty princesses so
the Bible says what let's read so I was
so I was
I'm here to talk to somebody who's
really been discouraged
Let me talk to you.
Your answer is not in calling another
man.
Your answer is in God placing his hand
on you so that you may experience his
mercy and grace and that he may pull you
out of that situation.
Discouragement, frustration is not your
portion.
So right now as I'm speaking, we rebuke
that spirit of discouragement.
That spirit that makes people feel not
wanted. That spirit that makes people
feel rejected, dejected, stressed up,
depressed, that spirit that makes people
feel frustrated. We rebuke it right now
and we declare the hand of God is COMING
UPON YOU. YOU WILL BE ENCOURAGED. I SAY
YOU SHALL BE ENCOURAGED. I SAY YOU SHALL
BE ENCOURAGED. RECEIVE ENCOURAGEMENT
TODAY. This preaching was for a people
who have desired to go to the next
level, accomplish a great assignment
over their lives AND THEY WERE WONDERING
HOW WILL I DO IT. I CAME to let you know
the hand of God will be upon you. The
hand of God will be upon you. It will
not be impossible. The hand of God will
be upon you. WORSHIP HIM. THE HAND OF
GOD WILL BE UPON YOU. THE HAND OF GOD IS
COMING UPON YOU. STAND UP ON YOUR FEET
AND LOOK FOR FIVE PEOPLE AND TELL THEM
THE HAND OF GOD WILL BE UPON YOU FROM
NOW GOING ON IN THE MIGHTY NAME OF
JESUS.
OH, I DON'T SEE YOU TALKING TO YOUR
NEIGHBOR. TELL YOUR NEIGHBOR, NEIGHBOR,
THE HAND OF GOD IS coming upon you. The
hand of God is COMING UPON YOU. THE HAND
OF GOD WILL MAKE YOU EXCEPTIONAL. THE
HAND OF GOD WILL MARK YOU. THE HAND OF
GOD WILL EMPOWER YOU. THE HAND OF GOD
WILL ENDORSE YOU. THE HAND OF GOD WILL
EXCEL YOU. THE HAND OF GOD WHO WILL
ELEVATE YOU. YOU NEED THE HAND OF GOD
UPON YOUR LIFE. UH OPEN UP YOUR MOUTH
AND GIVE THE LORD A MIGHTY HAND AND A
SHOUT OF PRAISE. GLORIFY HIM. UH HE'S
MORE THAN READY. HE'S MORE THAN WILLING
TO DO EXCEEDINGLY ABUNDANTLY. MORE THAN
YOU THINK OR EVEN IMAGINE. BLESS THE
NAME OF THE LORD. BLESS THE NAME OF THE
LORD. CLAP YOUR HANDS ALL YE PEOPLE.
SHOUT OUT TO GOD
>> WITH A VOICE OF TRIUMPH. BLESS THE LORD.
BLESS THE LORD. BLESS THE LORD. VICTORY
IS YOURS. VICTORY IS YOURS. YOU'RE
COMING OUT. YOU'RE COMING OUT. YOU SHALL
BE BETTER. SHOUT A BIG AMEN.
Oh
God,
>> why don't you GIVE THE LORD ONE more
round of applause? Give him the praise.
>> Give him the praise.
>> You're so good.
>> Lift those hands before God right now.
God,
you're so good. I believe
God. Take your
God to work.
You're so good.
I want you to say
oh your soul
forever.
I will take I will take you to your
soul. Do you believe
to be
your
for me
with every head bowed and one hand
lifted before God right now.
God's hand is coming upon you right now.
You're going to experience significant
change in your life.
Tremendous changes are coming over you
right now. Right now in this atmosphere,
somebody is re receiving their
elevation. Right now,
somebody is receiving exceptional grace
over their lives. Right now, right now,
it's happening right now.
Somebody's receiving encouragement right
now. Right now, it's happening. It's
happening. I see it happening. I see
somebody being earmarked.
You've been ignored for long, but God is
here marking you right now. They will
not help it, but recognize you. I see it
happening right now. Right now. Right
now.
Father, we thank you. Father, we give
you praise. Thank you for your favor.
Thank you for your blessing. Thank you
for your good hand upon our lives. We
are totally changed. We are totally
changed. Thank you for your presence and
thank you for your power
in Jesus name we pray. Shout a big amen.
>> Put your hands together. Bless the name
of Jesus. One more time. God,
you're so good. Come on, sing. Say, God,
you're so good.
>> I lift you up.
You're so good.
You're so good
to
me.
>> High five your neighbor for me and tell
them the good hand of the Lord is upon
you.
The good hand of the Lord. Smile at
them. Please smile at them. Tell them
the good hand of the Lord. The good
hand. The good hand. The good hand of
the Lord is upon you. The good hand of
the Lord is upon you. Amen.
>> Amen. One more time, let's celebrate the
King of Kings.
We have your seats in Lord's presence.